
{
    "labs": [
        {
            "name": "Simple File Commands",
            "tasks": [
                {
                    "id": 1,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "Display your current working directory.",
                    "answer": "pwd"
                },
                {
                    "id": 2,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "Change to your home directory.",
                    "answer": "cd ~"
                },
                {
                    "id": 3,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "Display the contents of your current directory.",
                    "answer": "ls"
                },
                {
                    "id": 4,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "Display all files including hidden directories.",
                    "answer": "ls -a"
                },
                {
                    "id": 5,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "Display a long list of the contents of the current working directory.",
                    "answer": "ls -l"
                },
                {
                    "id": 6,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "Display the file types of the current working directory.",
                    "answer": "ls -F"
                },
                {
                    "id": 7,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "Return to your home directory.",
                    "answer": "cd ~"
                },
                {
                    "id": 8,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "Display the contents of the '/etc/default/keyboard' file.",
                    "answer": "cat /etc/default/keyboard"
                },
                {
                    "id": 9,
                    "type": "multi-choice",
                    "prompt": "Under what circumstance must you refrain from using the cat command to view the contents of a file?",
                    "answers": [
                        "a. Never, you can always use cat.",
                        "b. You cannot cat executable files.",
                        "c. You cannot cat json files."
                    ],
                    "answer": "b"
                },
                {
                    "id": 10,
                    "type": "multi-answer",
                    "prompt": "Display the contents of the '/etc/default/keyboard' file and the '/etc/default/cron file",
                    "answers": [
                        "cat /etc/default/keyboard / /etc/default/cron",
                        "more /etc/default/keyboard /etc/default/cron"
                    ]
                },
                {
                    "id": 11,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "Display the contents of the '/etc/default/keyboard' file and the '/etc/default/cron' file using a single command.",
                    "answer": "more /etc/default/keyboard /etc/default/cron"
                },
                {
                    "id": 12,
                    "type": "multi-choice",
                    "prompt": "What does the symbol '~' represent?",
                    "answers": [
                        "a. It is a shortcut for the users home directory.",
                        "b. It doesn't have anything to do with linux.",
                        "c. It is a shortcut for the root directory."
                    ],
                    "answer": "a"
                },
                {
                    "id": 13,
                    "type": "multi-choice",
                    "prompt": "Complete the missing options to the mv command and their descriptions below:\n\n -i \n",
                    "answers": [
                        "a. Ignore mode - ignores system advice.",
                        "b. Interactive mode - helps to prevent accidental overwriting.",
                        "c. Invalid option for mv."
                    ],
                    "answer": "b"
                },
                {
                    "id": 14,
                    "type": "multi-choice",
                    "prompt": "\n -r \n",
                    "answers": [
                        "a. Removes redundant files at new location.",
                        "b. Invalid option for mv.",
                        "c. Includes the content of a directory, including the contents of all subdirectories when you copy a directory."
                    ],
                    "answer": "c"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "name": "File Redirection and Pipes",
            "tasks": [
                {
                    "id": 1,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "Type the who command and use redirection, a pipe or appending in order to see the output when using the sort command from a single command line entry.",
                    "answer": "who | sort"
                },
                {
                    "id": 2,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "What type of operation enables you to send the output of a command directly to a file?",
                    "answer": "redirection"
                },
                {
                    "id": 3,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "Which operation allows you to send the output of a command to the bottom of a file (if that file already exists)?",
                    "answer": "appending"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "name": "Unix Meta-characters, Filenames and How to Use Man Pages",
            "tasks": [
                {
                    "id": 1,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "From the command line list only file or directory names that begin with the letter 'b'.",
                    "answer": "ls b*"
                },
                {
                    "id": 2,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "From your home directory use the “?” metacharacter to find an file or directory that ends with 'eans'.",
                    "answer": "ls ?eans"
                },
                {
                    "id": 3,
                    "type": "multi-choice",
                    "prompt": "If you issue the command ls ?* what is the result? Why do you think you get that result?",
                    "answers": [
                        "a. ",
                        "b. You will see a recursive listing of everything in the directory and all subsequent subdirectories.",
                        "c. "
                    ],
                    "answer": "b"
                },
                {
                    "id": 4,
                    "type": "multi-choice",
                    "prompt": "What special characters must be avoided when creating a file name?",
                    "answers": [
                        "a. / * & %",
                        "b. @ # $ ^",
                        "c. ! ? + ="
                    ],
                    "answer": "a"
                },
                {
                    "id": 5,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "What command do you enter to obtain help on how to use a command?",
                    "answer": "man"
                },
                {
                    "id": 6,
                    "type": "multi-choice",
                    "prompt": "What does the whatis command do?",
                    "answers": [
                        "a. It displays the full manual page for the command.",
                        "b. It shows all the available options for a command.",
                        "c. It gives a one-line description of the command, but omits any information about options etc."
                    ],
                    "answer": "c"
                },
                {
                    "id": 7,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "What command can you enter to find the name of the command if you aren’t sure of the exact name?",
                    "answer": "apropos"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "name": "Security",
            "tasks": [
                {
                    "id": 1,
                    "type": "table",
                    "prompt": "-rw-r--r-- 1 root root 984 Sep 25 15:56 /etc/group\ndrwxr-xr-x 2 root root 4096 Sep 16 20:39 /etc/skel\ndrwxrwxrwx 3 root root 984 Sep 25 15:56 /etc/motd\n\nFill in the permission sets and write the 3 digit octal number that represents the permission sets in the format:",
                    "format": "owner group other octal-value",
                    "values": [
                        "group",
                        "skel",
                        "motd"
                    ],
                    "answers": [
                        "rw- r-- r-- 644",
                        "rwx r-x r-x 755",
                        "rwx rwx rwx 777"
                    ]
                },
                {
                    "id": 2,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "Create a new file and a new directory – what are the permissions?",
                    "answer": "rw- r-- r--"
                },
		{
		    "id": 3,
		    "type": "multi-choice",
		    "prompt": "Distinguish between the symbolic and octal modes.",
		    "answers": [
			    "a. Symbolic mode uses numeric values, while octal mode uses symbols like rwx.",
			    "b. Symbolic mode is only used for directories, and octal mode is used for files.",
			    "c. Symbolic uses symbols as seen above—there are symbolic permissions rw- r--r--. The octal equivalent is 644."
	            ],
	    	    "answer": "c"
		},
                {
                    "id": 4,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "Using symbolic permissions add write permissions for the group to the /etc/skel file.",
                    "answer": "chmod g+a /etc/skel"
                },
                {
                    "id": 5,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "Using octal mode, change permissions on the motd file to –rwxrw----.",
                    "answer": "chmod 740 /etc/motd"
                },
                {
                    "id": 6,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "Using octal mode add write permissions for other on the file named group.",
                    "answer": "chmod 646 /etc/group"
                },
                {
                    "id": 7,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "Identify the UID and the GID for the group file. Which command did you use?",
                    "answer": "ls –n motd"
                },
                {
                    "id": 8,
                    "type": "multi-choice",
                    "prompt": "What does the ps command display?",
                    "answers": [
                        "a. It lists all the files in the current directory.",
                        "b. It gives you information about your processes, and their associated PID and status.",
                        "c. It shows the disk usage of your file system."
                    ],
                    "answer": "b"
                },
		{
		    "id": 9,
	            "type": "multi-choice",
	            "prompt": "What does the ps command display?",
	            "answers": [
			    "a. A process ID.",
			    "b. The current memory usage of the system.",
			    "c. The list of open files on the system."
		    ],
		    "answer": "a"
		},
                {
                    "id": 10,
                    "type": "multi-choice",
                    "prompt": "What options to the kill command were discussed in the slide notes?",
                    "answers": [
                        "a. -15 and -1.",
                        "b. -HUP and -INT.",
                        "c. Default and -9."
                    ],
                    "answer": "c"
                },
                {
                    "id": 11,
                    "type": "multi-choice",
                    "prompt": "What does -9 to the kill command represent? Is this the default option to the kill command? If this is not what is? What does this default option do?",
                    "answers": [
                        "a. It is a restart option for the kill command. -1 is the default, and it restarts the process.",
                        "b. It is an absolute kill option. This is not the default option and it is meant to be used as an absolute last resort. -15 is the default. It sends a terminate signal to a process but this is a more graceful kill than a -9 kill.",
                        "c. It pauses the process temporarily. -HUP is the default option."
                    ],
                    "answer": "b"
                },
                {
                    "id": 12,
                    "type": "multi-choice",
                    "prompt": "How do you send a process to the background? What does this mean?",
                    "answers": [
                        "a. You type control z, then at the prompt type bg.",
                        "b. You type control c, then restart the process in the background.",
                        "c. You type fg to force the process into the background."
                    ],
                    "answer": "a"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "name": "Other useful UNIX commands",
            "tasks": [
                {
                    "id": 1,
                    "type": "multi-choice",
                    "prompt": "What does the quota command do?",
                    "answers": [
                        "a. It displays the number of running processes on the system.",
                        "b. It shows the disk usage of the entire file system.",
                        "c. All students are allocated a certain amount of disk space on the file system for their personal files, usually about 100Mb."
                    ],
                    "answer": "c"
                },
                {
                    "id": 2,
                    "type": "multi-choice",
                    "prompt": "What is the difference between the df and du commands?",
                    "answers": [
                        "a. The df command shows the number of files, and the du command lists active processes.",
                        "b. The df command outputs network usage, while the du command lists disk errors.",
                        "c. The df command reports on the space left on the file system. The du command outputs the number of kilobytes used by each subdirectory."
                    ],
                    "answer": "c"
                },
                {
                    "id": 3,
                    "type": "multi-choice",
                    "prompt": "What does the gzip command do?",
                    "answers": [
                        "a. This reduces the size of a file, thus freeing valuable disk space.",
                        "b. It removes all files from a directory.",
                        "c. It duplicates a file with a different extension."
                    ],
                    "answer": "a"
                },
                {
                    "id": 4,
                    "type": "multi-choice",
                    "prompt": "How does zcat differ from the normal compression commands?",
                    "answers": [
                        "a. It compresses files to a larger size than the original.",
                        "b. It will read gzipped files without needing to uncompress them first.",
                        "c. It encrypts files during the compression process."
                    ],
                    "answer": "b"
                },
                {
                    "id": 5,
                    "type": "multi-choice",
                    "prompt": "What does the file command identify?",
                    "answers": [
                        "a. It classifies the named files according to the type of data they contain, for example ASCII (text), pictures, compressed data, etc.",
                        "b. It changes the file permissions for the specified files.",
                        "c. It renames files based on their content type."
                    ],
                    "answer": "a"
                },
                {
                    "id": 6,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "Demonstrate the diff command comparing file1 to file2",
                    "answer": "diff file1 file2"
                },
                {
                    "id": 7,
                    "type": "multi-choice",
                    "prompt": "Why is the diff command useful?",
                    "answers": [
                        "a. Lines beginning with a < denote file1, while lines beginning with a > denote file2.",
                        "b. It merges two files into one combined document.",
                        "c. It deletes duplicate lines from a text file."
                    ],
                    "answer": "a"
                },
                {
                    "id": 8,
                    "type": "multi-choice",
                    "prompt": "How can you find all the different options to use with the find command?",
                    "answers": [
                        "a. Use the help command followed by find.",
                        "b. Look at the find documentation on the official website.",
                        "c. Execute the man command with the find argument."
                    ],
                    "answer": "c"
                },
                {
                    "id": 9,
                    "type": "multi-choice",
                    "prompt": "What does the history command do?",
                    "answers": [
                        "a. It deletes all previously executed commands from memory.",
                        "b. It shows a list of running processes in the terminal.",
                        "c. The bash shell keeps an ordered list of all the commands that you have entered. Each command is given a number according to the order it was entered."
                    ],
                    "answer": "c"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "name": "Variables",
            "tasks": [
                {
                    "id": 1,
                    "type": "multi-choice",
                    "prompt": "What is a variable?",
                    "answers": [
                        "a. It is a fixed value in memory that cannot be changed.",
                        "b. It is a container in memory that is used to store values.",
                        "c. It is a command that automatically runs scripts in the terminal."
                    ],
                    "answer": "b"
                },
                {
                    "id": 2,
                    "type": "multi-choice",
                    "prompt": "How do you assign a Unix variable a value?",
                    "answers": [
                        "a. history == 200",
                        "b. history=200",
                        "c. set history to 200"
                    ],
                    "answer": "b"
                },
                {
                    "id": 3,
                    "type": "multi-choice",
                    "prompt": "What is the difference between a shell variable and an environment variable?",
                    "answers": [
                        "a. A shell variable is only accessible during the login session, while an environment variable can be accessed only after the system reboots.",
                        "b. Shell variables store user inputs, while environment variables store system commands.",
                        "c. A shell variable is local to the shell it is assigned in. An environment variable has visibility into the value stored in that variable for subshell instances."
                    ],
                    "answer": "c"
                },
                {
                    "id": 4,
                    "type": "multi-choice",
                    "prompt": "How can I call for the value stored in a shell variable?",
                    "answers": [
                        "a. Use the echo command. Ex. echo $PATH",
                        "b. Use the `print` command. Ex. print $PATH",
                        "c. Use the `cat` command. Ex. cat $PATH"
                    ],
                    "answer": "a"
                },
                {
                    "id": 5,
                    "type": "multi-choice",
                    "prompt": "Are there other ways that I can store or assign a value to a variable?",
                    "answers": [
                        "a. Variables can only be stored by directly editing the system's kernel.",
                        "b. The only way to assign a value to a variable is by using the `set` command in the terminal.",
                        "c. You can use an initialization file like ~/.bashrc."
                    ],
                    "answer": "c"
                },
                {
                    "id": 6,
                    "type": "multi-choice",
                    "prompt": "What are initialization files used for?",
                    "answers": [
                        "a. Information in these files is used to set up your working environment. You typically store scripts or variables in these files and their values will be kept there for permanent accessibility.",
                        "b. Initialization files are only used to store temporary data that is deleted after the session ends.",
                        "c. These files are primarily used to compile source code during software installations."
                    ],
                    "answer": "a"
                },
                {
                    "id": 7,
                    "type": "multi-choice",
                    "prompt": "How do you set the PATH variable? What does this mean?",
                    "answers": [
                        "a. PATH=~$USER\nThis is incorrect because it will not append the existing PATH or provide the correct structure.",
                        "b. PATH=$PATH:~ was an example\nThis means that whenever there is an executable binary command or a shell script that you wish to execute, the kernel will use this variable to locate the binary or shell script for execution.",
                        "c. export PATH=~/bin:$PATH\nThis is incorrect as it misses adding the correct directory."
                    ],
                    "answer": "b"
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}
